<records><record><language>rus</language><publisher>Krylov State Research Centre</publisher><journalTitle>Transactions of the Krylov State Research Centre</journalTitle><issn>2542-2324</issn><eissn>2618-8244</eissn><publicationDate>2019-08-30</publicationDate><volume>389</volume><issue>3</issue><startPage>11</startPage><endPage>21</endPage><doi>10.24937/2542-2324-2019-3-389-11-21</doi><publisherRecordId>25422324</publisherRecordId><documentType>article</documentType><title language="eng">Ice resistance of ships in brash ice channel: calculation method</title><authors><author><name>Aleksey A. Dobrodeev</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author><author><name>Kirill Ye. Sazonov</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author></authors><affiliationsList><affiliationName affiliationId="1">JSC PO Sevmash</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="2">Admiral Makarov State University of Maritime and Inland Shipping</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="3">St. Petersburg State Marine Technical University</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="4">JSC Alexeev&#8217;s Hydrofoil Design Bureau</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="5">JSC CDB MT Rubin</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="6">RAS Institute of Applied Physics</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="7">JSC Giprorybflot.</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="8">Krylov State Research Centre</affiliationName></affiliationsList><abstract language="eng">Object and purpose of research. This paper discusses modern carrier ships and icebreakers operating in ice channels and harbours, typically filled with brash ice that always forms very quickly in regularly used passages due to harsh Arctic climate, thus seriously impeding navigation. The purpose of this study is to develop a calculation method for brash ice resistance that would facilitate theoretical estimates of ice propulsion performance for ships under design, and would also be helpful in planning their operation in Arctic conditions. Materials and methods. This paper theoretically describes the phenomena that accompany ship sailing in brash ice channel. Theoretical model is based on the data of full-scale trial data and the model tests performed in KSRC Ice Basin. Main results. Ice resistance calculation method for ship sailing in brash ice channel has been successfully developed. The effect of main parameters in the developed mathematical model has been thoroughly analysed. Calculation results have been compared versus available experimental data. Conclusion. The calculations performed as per this mathematical model for several notional large ice-going ships have shown that breadth and length of their parallel middlebodies, as well as bow shape, have the greatest effect upon resistance. Ice resistance tests performed in KSRC Ice Basin have shown a good correlation between experimental data and calculation results obtained as per the suggested procedure.</abstract><fullTextUrl format="pdf">http://transactions-ksrc.ru/eng/archive/Ice-resistance-of-ships-in-brash-ice-channel-calculation-method/</fullTextUrl><keywords language="eng"><keyword>brash ice</keyword><keyword>ice channel</keyword><keyword>ice resistance</keyword><keyword>friction force</keyword><keyword>buoyancy force</keyword></keywords></record><record><language>rus</language><publisher>Krylov State Research Centre</publisher><journalTitle>Transactions of the Krylov State Research Centre</journalTitle><issn>2542-2324</issn><eissn>2618-8244</eissn><publicationDate>2019-08-30</publicationDate><volume>389</volume><issue>3</issue><startPage>22</startPage><endPage>28</endPage><doi>10.24937/2542-2324-2019-3-389-22-28</doi><publisherRecordId>25422324</publisherRecordId><documentType>article</documentType><title language="eng">An experimental and analytical study of a titanium alloy cold creep in the pure bending conditions</title><authors><author><name>Vladimir I. Nigmatullin</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author><author><name>Oksana G. Rybakina</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author><author><name>Olga A. Strogonova</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author></authors><affiliationsList><affiliationName affiliationId="1">JSC PO Sevmash</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="2">Admiral Makarov State University of Maritime and Inland Shipping</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="3">St. Petersburg State Marine Technical University</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="4">JSC Alexeev&#8217;s Hydrofoil Design Bureau</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="5">JSC CDB MT Rubin</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="6">RAS Institute of Applied Physics</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="7">JSC Giprorybflot.</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="8">Krylov State Research Centre</affiliationName></affiliationsList><abstract language="eng">Object and purpose of research. This paper studies pure bending of titanium alloy strap with different properties in tension and compression under cold creep conditions. The effect of opposite-sign plastic strain on subsequent creep process is studied both analytically and experimentally. Materials and methods. Creep is described with the previously method based on the tests of samples performed at constant total strain rate in a wide range (5 orders of magnitude). The experiment was performed at Instron 8800-series test machines. Main results. Titanium alloy strap was subjected to pure bending. The bending moment and tension-compression strains on its surfaces were recorded. These data made it possible to obtain stress-strain diagrams for this material that coincided with the diagrams obtained independently for uniaxial tension and uniaxial compression. Analytical and experimental studies were performed in cold-creep conditions. Stress and strain distributions in the strap thickness were calculated for each moment of time. It has been shown that the creep is accompanied by stress redistribution in the strap thickness: the stresses near the surfaces relax, as a result the creep decelerates. The effect of pre-bending on subsequent creep of the strap turned upside down has also studied: it turned out that the creep strains in this case are greater than for the alloy in the initial state (this phenomenon is similar to Bauschinger effect). Conclusion. These results will enable structural calculations of titanium-alloy deepwater submersibles taking cold creep into account.</abstract><fullTextUrl format="pdf">http://transactions-ksrc.ru/eng/archive/An-experimental-and-analytical-study-of-a-titanium-alloy-cold-creep-in-the-pure-bending-conditions/</fullTextUrl><keywords language="eng"><keyword>deepwater submersibles</keyword><keyword>cold creep</keyword><keyword>titanium alloy</keyword><keyword>strain</keyword><keyword>tension</keyword><keyword>bending</keyword></keywords></record><record><language>rus</language><publisher>Krylov State Research Centre</publisher><journalTitle>Transactions of the Krylov State Research Centre</journalTitle><issn>2542-2324</issn><eissn>2618-8244</eissn><publicationDate>2019-08-30</publicationDate><volume>389</volume><issue>3</issue><startPage>29</startPage><endPage>36</endPage><doi>10.24937/2542-2324-2019-3-389-29-36</doi><publisherRecordId>25422324</publisherRecordId><documentType>article</documentType><title language="eng">Development of strength and stiffness requirements to hull framing beams made of polymeric composites</title><authors><author><name>Nikolay N. Fedonyuk</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author></authors><affiliationsList><affiliationName affiliationId="1">JSC PO Sevmash</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="2">Admiral Makarov State University of Maritime and Inland Shipping</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="3">St. Petersburg State Marine Technical University</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="4">JSC Alexeev&#8217;s Hydrofoil Design Bureau</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="5">JSC CDB MT Rubin</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="6">RAS Institute of Applied Physics</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="7">JSC Giprorybflot.</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="8">Krylov State Research Centre</affiliationName></affiliationsList><abstract language="eng">Object and purpose of research. This paper studies hull framing beams made of polymeric composite materials and discusses how to develop strength, stiffness and stability requirements for them. The main purpose of this research is to perform a comprehensive analysis of these parameters and understand their possible implications in terms of beam geometry and weight. Materials and methods. The study is based on existing design requirements and strength calculation rules for hull framing beams made of polymeric composites. The basis for investigation was the theory of complex beam bending taking into account transverse shear strains in the web. Main results. It has been shown that current bending limitations in a number of cases lead to considerable strength and stability margins of hull beams, thus increasing their weight per unit length. Meanwhile, minor deviations from bending requirements, under condition that strength and stability requirements are satisfied in full, may result in considerable reduction of beam weight. Conclusion. Bending limitations for composite hull beams must be justified depending on the importance of specific beam, as well as depending on its operational conditions and load. Beam design must be, first of all, focused on ensuring their bearing capacity. The results of this work will be helpful for designers of composite hulls, enabling them to reduce the weight of structures.</abstract><fullTextUrl format="pdf">http://transactions-ksrc.ru/eng/archive/development-of-strength-and-stiffness-requirements-to-hull-framing-beams-made-of-polymeric-composite/</fullTextUrl><keywords language="eng"><keyword>hull</keyword><keyword>beam</keyword><keyword>polymeric composite material</keyword><keyword>strength</keyword><keyword>stiffness</keyword><keyword>stability</keyword><keyword>regulations</keyword></keywords></record><record><language>rus</language><publisher>Krylov State Research Centre</publisher><journalTitle>Transactions of the Krylov State Research Centre</journalTitle><issn>2542-2324</issn><eissn>2618-8244</eissn><publicationDate>2019-08-30</publicationDate><volume>389</volume><issue>3</issue><startPage>37</startPage><endPage>48</endPage><doi>10.24937/2542-2324-2019-3-389-37-48</doi><publisherRecordId>25422324</publisherRecordId><documentType>article</documentType><title language="eng">On quasi-crash-stop model tests of marine propellers</title><authors><author><name>Valery M. Kotlovich</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author></authors><affiliationsList><affiliationName affiliationId="1">JSC PO Sevmash</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="2">Admiral Makarov State University of Maritime and Inland Shipping</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="3">St. Petersburg State Marine Technical University</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="4">JSC Alexeev&#8217;s Hydrofoil Design Bureau</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="5">JSC CDB MT Rubin</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="6">RAS Institute of Applied Physics</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="7">JSC Giprorybflot.</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="8">Krylov State Research Centre</affiliationName></affiliationsList><abstract language="eng">Object and purpose of research. This paper analyses the quasi-crash-stop model test data for propellers in open water and behind the hull of self-propelled ship models, as well as justifies a new method for presentation of the results and gives an approximate estimate for propeller-hull interaction in quasi-crash-stop conditions. Materials and methods. The study analyses existing methods for presentation of quasi-crash-stop propeller test data and justifies a new method that presents generalized thrust and torque coefficients as functions of &#946;A,B angle at which JA,B = tan &#946;A,B, where JA,B is advance ratio (A) or apparent advance (B) of the propeller. This method is extended to quasi-crash-stop tests of self-propelled ship models that give more complete information on crash-stop propeller parameters. The approximate analysis of hull-propeller interaction in various crash-stop scenarios given in this study has shown that actual thrust deduction coefficients and wake fractions of propellers are considerably different from those adopted at the design stage. Main results. The paper justifies a new method of quasi-crash-stop test data for propellers in open water and behind the hull, and also shows that actual propeller-hull interaction coefficients are different from those adopted at propeller design stage. Therefore, for practical purposes, quasi-crash-stop tests are preferable to perform on self-propelled models rather than isolated propellers. Conclusion. This paper could be helpful for quasi-crash-stop tests and design of propellers.</abstract><fullTextUrl format="pdf">http://transactions-ksrc.ru/eng/archive/On-quasi-crash-stop-model-tests-of-marine-propellers/</fullTextUrl><keywords language="eng"><keyword>crash stop</keyword><keyword>self-propulsion tests</keyword><keyword>crash-stop interaction</keyword></keywords></record><record><language>rus</language><publisher>Krylov State Research Centre</publisher><journalTitle>Transactions of the Krylov State Research Centre</journalTitle><issn>2542-2324</issn><eissn>2618-8244</eissn><publicationDate>2019-08-30</publicationDate><volume>389</volume><issue>3</issue><startPage>49</startPage><endPage>56</endPage><doi>10.24937/2542-2324-2019-3-389-49-56</doi><publisherRecordId>25422324</publisherRecordId><documentType>article</documentType><title language="eng">Cavitation noise of propeller models in uniform flow: full-scale extrapolation method</title><authors><author><name>Vadim P. Ilyin</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author><author><name>Yulia S. Yakovleva</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author></authors><affiliationsList><affiliationName affiliationId="1">JSC PO Sevmash</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="2">Admiral Makarov State University of Maritime and Inland Shipping</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="3">St. Petersburg State Marine Technical University</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="4">JSC Alexeev&#8217;s Hydrofoil Design Bureau</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="5">JSC CDB MT Rubin</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="6">RAS Institute of Applied Physics</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="7">JSC Giprorybflot.</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="8">Krylov State Research Centre</affiliationName></affiliationsList><abstract language="eng">Object and purpose of research. This paper discusses laboratory measurements of cavitation-induced noise of propeller models in uniform flow, as well as extrapolation of the model test data to the full scale. Materials and methods. The study is based on the model test data obtained in the cavitation tunnel for the models in uniform flow, as well as on extrapolation of these data to the non-uniform flow behind the hull, taking into account the laws of cavitation-induced noise simulation. Main results. This study made it possible to develop a prediction method for spectral levels of cavitation-induced noise radiated by the propeller, based on the model test data obtained in the cavitation tunnel, as well as to develop the method of model test data extrapolation to the non-uniform flow behind the hull. Conclusion. These results could be used to predict cavitation-induced noise of marine propellers at detailed de- sign stage.</abstract><fullTextUrl format="pdf">http://transactions-ksrc.ru/eng/archive/Cavitation-noise-of-propeller-models-in-uniform-flow-full-scale-extrapolation-method/</fullTextUrl><keywords language="eng"><keyword>propeller</keyword><keyword>cavitation-induced noise</keyword><keyword>acoustic measurements</keyword><keyword>cavitation tunnel</keyword></keywords></record><record><language>rus</language><publisher>Krylov State Research Centre</publisher><journalTitle>Transactions of the Krylov State Research Centre</journalTitle><issn>2542-2324</issn><eissn>2618-8244</eissn><publicationDate>2019-08-30</publicationDate><volume>389</volume><issue>3</issue><startPage>57</startPage><endPage>62</endPage><doi>10.24937/2542-2324-2019-3-389-57-62</doi><publisherRecordId>25422324</publisherRecordId><documentType>article</documentType><title language="eng">Crash-stop of complex-geometry propellers: stressed-state specifics</title><authors><author><name>Leonid I. Vishnevsky</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author><author><name>Dyk Chin Luk</name><affiliationId>3</affiliationId></author></authors><affiliationsList><affiliationName affiliationId="1">JSC PO Sevmash</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="2">Admiral Makarov State University of Maritime and Inland Shipping</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="3">St. Petersburg State Marine Technical University</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="4">JSC Alexeev&#8217;s Hydrofoil Design Bureau</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="5">JSC CDB MT Rubin</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="6">RAS Institute of Applied Physics</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="7">JSC Giprorybflot.</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="8">Krylov State Research Centre</affiliationName></affiliationsList><abstract language="eng">Object and purpose of research. This work analyses stressed state of propeller with complex geometry depending on its operational conditions, including crash-stop scenario. Materials and methods. The study is based on laboratory and full-scale test data. Main results. It has been shown that blade strains of complex-geometry propellers under hydrodynamic loads must be sufficient to alter their hydrodynamic performance. It is pointed out that stresses in these propellers could be especially hazardous in terms of reliability in crash-stop conditions. Conclusion. This paper shows that low-speed propellers cannot be taken as design prototypes for high-speed propellers with complex geometry, otherwise there might be reliability implications.</abstract><fullTextUrl format="pdf">http://transactions-ksrc.ru/eng/archive/Crash-stop-of-complex-geometry-propellers-stressed-state-specifics/</fullTextUrl><keywords language="eng"><keyword>propeller</keyword><keyword>cavitation-induced noise</keyword><keyword>acoustic measurements</keyword><keyword>cavitation tunnel</keyword></keywords></record><record><language>rus</language><publisher>Krylov State Research Centre</publisher><journalTitle>Transactions of the Krylov State Research Centre</journalTitle><issn>2542-2324</issn><eissn>2618-8244</eissn><publicationDate>2019-08-30</publicationDate><volume>389</volume><issue>3</issue><startPage>63</startPage><endPage>72</endPage><doi>10.24937/2542-2324-2019-3-389-63-72</doi><publisherRecordId>25422324</publisherRecordId><documentType>article</documentType><title language="eng">Cavitation inception calculation for pumpjet impeller</title><authors><author><name>Mikhail P. Lobachev</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author><author><name>Alexey A. Rudnichenko</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author></authors><affiliationsList><affiliationName affiliationId="1">JSC PO Sevmash</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="2">Admiral Makarov State University of Maritime and Inland Shipping</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="3">St. Petersburg State Marine Technical University</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="4">JSC Alexeev&#8217;s Hydrofoil Design Bureau</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="5">JSC CDB MT Rubin</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="6">RAS Institute of Applied Physics</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="7">JSC Giprorybflot.</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="8">Krylov State Research Centre</affiliationName></affiliationsList><abstract language="eng">Object and purpose of research. This paper studies pumpjets with short ducts to develop a calculation procedure for cavitation inception in model test conditions. Materials and methods. The moment of cavitation inception is determined visually, by observation of the cavitation tunnel test. The conditions of physical test have been thoroughly replicated in a computer-based simulation by means of state-of-the-art numerical methods and high-end hardware. Main results. This paper suggests a method of cavitation inception determination that relies on the results of numerical pumpjet flow simulation based on Reynolds equations. Two variants of this method are discussed: the first one tackles depressurization areas (without calculating the vaporization process, i.e. cavitation itself), whereas the second one does calculate cavitation by means of Schnerr and Sauer model. Simulation results are compared versus the test data where cavitation inception is determined visually. The criteria of cavitation inception suggested in this paper are, in the first variant, the volume of depressurization domains or, in the second variant, the volume of cavities defined as the areas with 5% vapour content. For standard conditions of model tests (impeller diameter 200-250 mm) this volume is 1 mm3. Conclusion. The method of cavitation inception determination suggested in this paper is sufficiently accurate for practical purposes. For impellers with blade geometry close to the one discussed in this paper, the method can predict cavitation inception without calculation of vaporization itself, which gives four-fold gain in the hardware resources required for calculation. Both variants of this method will be especially helpful for studies on the effect of local changes in impeller blade geometry upon cavitation inception.</abstract><fullTextUrl format="pdf">http://transactions-ksrc.ru/eng/archive/Cavitation-inception-calculation-for-pumpjet-impeller/</fullTextUrl><keywords language="eng"><keyword>impeller</keyword><keyword>pumpjet</keyword><keyword>cavitation</keyword><keyword>Reynolds equations</keyword><keyword>numerical simulation</keyword></keywords></record><record><language>rus</language><publisher>Krylov State Research Centre</publisher><journalTitle>Transactions of the Krylov State Research Centre</journalTitle><issn>2542-2324</issn><eissn>2618-8244</eissn><publicationDate>2019-08-30</publicationDate><volume>389</volume><issue>3</issue><startPage>73</startPage><endPage>82</endPage><doi>10.24937/2542-2324-2019-3-389-73-82</doi><publisherRecordId>25422324</publisherRecordId><documentType>article</documentType><title language="eng">Determination of local and integral parameters for container cargo carrier in digital basin</title><authors><author><name>Andrey Ye. Taranov</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author></authors><affiliationsList><affiliationName affiliationId="1">JSC PO Sevmash</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="2">Admiral Makarov State University of Maritime and Inland Shipping</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="3">St. Petersburg State Marine Technical University</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="4">JSC Alexeev&#8217;s Hydrofoil Design Bureau</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="5">JSC CDB MT Rubin</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="6">RAS Institute of Applied Physics</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="7">JSC Giprorybflot.</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="8">Krylov State Research Centre</affiliationName></affiliationsList><abstract language="eng">Object and purpose of research. This paper is intended to validate the set of CFD technologies for viscous fluid (digital basin) by means of the case study (investigation of KCS container ship model parameters). Materials and methods. Local and integral hydrodynamic parameters of the container ship are investigated by means of CFD tools. Viscous flow parameters are obtained through control-volume solution of unsteady Reynolds equations, closed by bi-parametric semi-empirical turbulence model. Numerical simulation technologies are validated by extensive test data obtained by various test tanks. Main results. Validation of the CFD tool set by means of the flow studies of KSC container ship and her propeller (calculation of towing resistance, trim &amp; draft parameters, propeller performance curves, nominal wake field, hull resistance and trim &amp; draft parameters in head waves, and also numerical simulation of self-propulsion tests) and by comparison of these data versus experimental results has confirmed high accuracy of modern calculation methods. Conclusion. KSRC experience of numerical studies shows that the scope of tasks handled by numerical simulation is steadily becoming wider and wider. Applications of CFD methods in marine hydrodynamics enhances the potential of conventional test facilities in the studies on specifics of certain physical processes. Here, analysis of local flow peculiarities and their time history, as well as accuracy of full-scale predictions for ship under design, become very important.</abstract><fullTextUrl format="pdf">http://transactions-ksrc.ru/eng/archive/Determination-of-local-and-integral-parameters-for-container-cargo-carrier-in-digital-basin/</fullTextUrl><keywords language="eng"><keyword>numerical simulation</keyword><keyword>physical modeling</keyword><keyword>validation</keyword><keyword>digital basin</keyword></keywords></record><record><language>rus</language><publisher>Krylov State Research Centre</publisher><journalTitle>Transactions of the Krylov State Research Centre</journalTitle><issn>2542-2324</issn><eissn>2618-8244</eissn><publicationDate>2019-08-30</publicationDate><volume>389</volume><issue>3</issue><startPage>83</startPage><endPage>94</endPage><doi>10.24937/2542-2324-2019-3-389-83-94</doi><publisherRecordId>25422324</publisherRecordId><documentType>article</documentType><title language="eng">Two-staged blade propulsor with dual-action counter-propeller and its design solutions</title><authors><author><name>Anatoly R. Togunjac</name><affiliationId>7</affiliationId></author><author><name>Leonid I. Vishnevskij</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author></authors><affiliationsList><affiliationName affiliationId="1">JSC PO Sevmash</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="2">Admiral Makarov State University of Maritime and Inland Shipping</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="3">St. Petersburg State Marine Technical University</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="4">JSC Alexeev&#8217;s Hydrofoil Design Bureau</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="5">JSC CDB MT Rubin</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="6">RAS Institute of Applied Physics</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="7">JSC Giprorybflot.</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="8">Krylov State Research Centre</affiliationName></affiliationsList><abstract language="eng">Object and purpose of research. This paper studies multi-purpose two-staged blade propulsor with counter-propeller in order to improve control and power efficiency of ship. Materials and methods. The study is based on model test data and calculation results. Main results. Taking a large fishing vessel as a case study, this paper demonstrates the efficiency of dual-action counter-propeller as active ship control tool and compares it versus conventional tunnel thruster. Conclusion. A ship equipped with the system suggested in this paper may receive an additional symbol to its RS class notation: redundancy of propulsion system elements.</abstract><fullTextUrl format="pdf">http://transactions-ksrc.ru/eng/archive/Two-staged-blade-propulsor-with-dual-action-counter-propeller-and-its-design-solutions/</fullTextUrl><keywords language="eng"><keyword>multi-functional two-staged blade propulsor</keyword><keyword>dual-action counter-propeller</keyword><keyword>power saving</keyword><keyword>emergency sailing</keyword></keywords></record><record><language>rus</language><publisher>Krylov State Research Centre</publisher><journalTitle>Transactions of the Krylov State Research Centre</journalTitle><issn>2542-2324</issn><eissn>2618-8244</eissn><publicationDate>2019-08-30</publicationDate><volume>389</volume><issue>3</issue><startPage>95</startPage><endPage>102</endPage><doi>10.24937/2542-2324-2019-3-389-95-102</doi><publisherRecordId>25422324</publisherRecordId><documentType>article</documentType><title language="eng">Uuv launch/recovery moonpool aboard ships: arrangement peculiarities</title><authors><author><name>Grigory P. Kuznetsov</name><affiliationId>4</affiliationId></author><author><name>Ivan N. Buldakov</name><affiliationId>4</affiliationId></author></authors><affiliationsList><affiliationName affiliationId="1">JSC PO Sevmash</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="2">Admiral Makarov State University of Maritime and Inland Shipping</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="3">St. Petersburg State Marine Technical University</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="4">JSC Alexeev&#8217;s Hydrofoil Design Bureau</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="5">JSC CDB MT Rubin</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="6">RAS Institute of Applied Physics</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="7">JSC Giprorybflot.</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="8">Krylov State Research Centre</affiliationName></affiliationsList><abstract language="eng">Object and purpose of research. This paper studies design technologies for large sea-going research vessel with onboard helicopter and deepwater submersible vehicle (DSV) launched/recovered via the moonpool passing through hull and superstructure. The purpose of this study is to ensure permanent helicopter base aboard research vessel, as well as DSV launch/recovery via the moonpool in the open sea. Materials and methods. The study was intended to find an optimal even-keel trimming solution for a ship with spacious forward moonpool for large deepwater submersibles, as well as to develop an optimal procedure of DSV launching/recovery. Main results. The study yielded an original technological solution for even-keel trimming of ship with large forward moonpool, as well as an original technology for Bester-1 DSV launch/recovery. Conclusion. The solution suggested in this paper enabled even-keel trimming of ship without prejudice to her propulsion performance. The newly developed technology of Bester-1 DSV launch/recovery via the moonpool will considerably expand the spectrum of tasks handled by the research ship, including the operations in polar waters.</abstract><fullTextUrl format="pdf">http://transactions-ksrc.ru/eng/archive/Uuv-launch/recovery-moonpool-aboard-ships:-arrangement-peculiarities/</fullTextUrl><keywords language="eng"><keyword>research ship</keyword><keyword>moonpool</keyword><keyword>watertight bottom closing</keyword><keyword>ballasted reservoir</keyword><keyword>deepwater submersible vehicle</keyword><keyword>positioning system</keyword></keywords></record><record><language>rus</language><publisher>Krylov State Research Centre</publisher><journalTitle>Transactions of the Krylov State Research Centre</journalTitle><issn>2542-2324</issn><eissn>2618-8244</eissn><publicationDate>2019-08-30</publicationDate><volume>389</volume><issue>3</issue><startPage>103</startPage><endPage>112</endPage><doi>10.24937/2542-2324-2019-3-389-103-112</doi><publisherRecordId>25422324</publisherRecordId><documentType>article</documentType><title language="eng">Vector control algorithm for electric propulsion drives with synchronous motors for icebreakers with azipods</title><authors><author><name>Viktor I. Vershinin</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author><author><name>Sergey V. Makhonin</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author><author><name>Vladimir A. Parshikov</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author><author><name>Valentin A. Khomyak</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author></authors><affiliationsList><affiliationName affiliationId="1">JSC PO Sevmash</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="2">Admiral Makarov State University of Maritime and Inland Shipping</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="3">St. Petersburg State Marine Technical University</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="4">JSC Alexeev&#8217;s Hydrofoil Design Bureau</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="5">JSC CDB MT Rubin</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="6">RAS Institute of Applied Physics</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="7">JSC Giprorybflot.</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="8">Krylov State Research Centre</affiliationName></affiliationsList><abstract language="eng">Object and purpose of research. This paper studies electric drives of pod propulsion units installed at heavy-duty icebreakers of the new generations: their electric propulsion systems are based on synchronous motors and static frequency converters. The purpose of this work is to develop a flow chart and investigate electromechanical properties of vector-controlled synchronous propulsion drive that meets stringent requirements to the dynamics of electric propulsion systems aboard new-generation icebreakers. Materials and methods. The study is based on the data available in theoretical literature on electric drives, as well as on personal findings and experience of the authors gained in numerous R&amp;D projects on marine electric propulsion systems. The method followed by the authors is based on the possibility to simulate various electromechanical devices and systems in Simulink application and Sim Power Systems library of MATLAB software package. Main results. The main result of this study is the flow chart of propulsion drive based on 6.5MW synchronous motor: this system is not only as fast and accurate in terms of output coordinates as the best examples of DC and frequency-controlled AC drives, but excels them in terms of power efficiency. Conclusion. Practical findings of the authors could be helpful in development of propulsion drives based on synchronous motors for electric propulsion system of advanced new-generation icebreakers.</abstract><fullTextUrl format="pdf">http://transactions-ksrc.ru/eng/archive/vector-control-algorithm-for-electric-propulsion-drives-with-synchronous-motors-for-icebreakers-with/</fullTextUrl><keywords language="eng"><keyword>electric propulsion system</keyword><keyword>propulsion drive</keyword><keyword>pod propulsion unit</keyword><keyword>static converter</keyword><keyword>synchronous motor</keyword><keyword>vector- based control</keyword><keyword>conversion of coordinates</keyword><keyword>rotor position gauge</keyword></keywords></record><record><language>rus</language><publisher>Krylov State Research Centre</publisher><journalTitle>Transactions of the Krylov State Research Centre</journalTitle><issn>2542-2324</issn><eissn>2618-8244</eissn><publicationDate>2019-08-30</publicationDate><volume>389</volume><issue>3</issue><startPage>113</startPage><endPage>120</endPage><doi>10.24937/2542-2324-2019-3-389-113-120</doi><publisherRecordId>25422324</publisherRecordId><documentType>article</documentType><title language="eng">Detection of fuel overconsumption by marine diesel genset</title><authors><author><name>Sergey E. Kuznetsov</name><affiliationId>2</affiliationId></author><author><name>Nikolay A. Alekseev</name><affiliationId>2</affiliationId></author><author><name>Andrey Aleksandrovich Vinogradov</name><affiliationId>2</affiliationId></author></authors><affiliationsList><affiliationName affiliationId="1">JSC PO Sevmash</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="2">Admiral Makarov State University of Maritime and Inland Shipping</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="3">St. Petersburg State Marine Technical University</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="4">JSC Alexeev&#8217;s Hydrofoil Design Bureau</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="5">JSC CDB MT Rubin</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="6">RAS Institute of Applied Physics</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="7">JSC Giprorybflot.</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="8">Krylov State Research Centre</affiliationName></affiliationsList><abstract language="eng">Object and purpose of research. This paper studies diesel gensets with medium-speed diesels and three-phase synchronous brushless generators. The purpose of the study was to obtain calculation formula for possible fuel overconsumption in specific operational conditions of ship power plant. Materials and methods. The study relied on factory test data given in technical certificates of specific diesel gensets, namely consumption and specific consumption of fuel at different electric loads and power coefficient cos&#966; = 1. Main results. This study yielded the formula for fuel consumption depending on electric load and power coefficient cos&#966; - Q (P&#1043;, cos&#966;) for an operational diesel genset running on its intended diesel fuel. This expression, Q (P&#1043;, cos&#966;), is used to calculate fuel consumption for specific values of power and cos&#966;, i.e. for any scenario of ship operation. Possible overconsumption of fuel is determined through comparison of actual fuel consumption (as measured by standard flow meter aboard the ship) at given electric load versus the consumption obtained as per Q (P&#1043;, cos&#966;) expression for the same values of load and cos&#966;. Significant overconsumption of fuel might imply that diesel genset is not in good order or that its current fuel is not optimal. Conclusion. Once significant overconsumption of fuel is detected, the crew must take appropriate measures to fix this problem. The procedure described in this paper enables technical monitoring of marine diesel gensets and optimal selection of their respective fuels.</abstract><fullTextUrl format="pdf">http://transactions-ksrc.ru/eng/archive/Detection-of-fuel-overconsumption-by-marine-diesel-genset/</fullTextUrl><keywords language="eng"><keyword>marine diesel genset</keyword><keyword>fuel overconsumption</keyword><keyword>power</keyword><keyword>load coefficient</keyword><keyword>specific fuel consumption</keyword><keyword>calculation procedure</keyword></keywords></record><record><language>rus</language><publisher>Krylov State Research Centre</publisher><journalTitle>Transactions of the Krylov State Research Centre</journalTitle><issn>2542-2324</issn><eissn>2618-8244</eissn><publicationDate>2019-08-30</publicationDate><volume>389</volume><issue>3</issue><startPage>121</startPage><endPage>126</endPage><doi>10.24937/2542-2324-2019-3-389-121-126</doi><publisherRecordId>25422324</publisherRecordId><documentType>article</documentType><title language="eng">Electrodynamic forces in two-layered coils</title><authors><author><name>Georgy N. Tsitsikyan</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author><author><name>Mikhail Yu. Antipov</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author><author><name>Yury D. Baranov</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author></authors><affiliationsList><affiliationName affiliationId="1">JSC PO Sevmash</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="2">Admiral Makarov State University of Maritime and Inland Shipping</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="3">St. Petersburg State Marine Technical University</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="4">JSC Alexeev&#8217;s Hydrofoil Design Bureau</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="5">JSC CDB MT Rubin</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="6">RAS Institute of Applied Physics</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="7">JSC Giprorybflot.</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="8">Krylov State Research Centre</affiliationName></affiliationsList><abstract language="eng">Object and purpose of research. This paper discusses two-layered solenoid of loading device. The purpose is to obtain correct estimate of electrodynamic forces acting on extreme loops of external and internal solenoid layers. Materials and methods. The study follows the expressions for electrodynamic forces, with application of special functions. Main results. Development of electrodynamic force calculation method for two-layered solenoids by means of an auxiliary functions (its values are given in tabular form). Conclusion. The paper demonstrates an example of electrodynamic force calculations for loading device solenoids intended to test power plants of ships.</abstract><fullTextUrl format="pdf">http://transactions-ksrc.ru/eng/archive/Electrodynamic-forces-in-two-layered-coils/</fullTextUrl><keywords language="eng"><keyword>two-layered solenoid</keyword><keyword>electrodynamic forces</keyword><keyword>loading devices</keyword></keywords></record><record><language>rus</language><publisher>Krylov State Research Centre</publisher><journalTitle>Transactions of the Krylov State Research Centre</journalTitle><issn>2542-2324</issn><eissn>2618-8244</eissn><publicationDate>2019-08-30</publicationDate><volume>389</volume><issue>3</issue><startPage>127</startPage><endPage>138</endPage><doi>10.24937/2542-2324-2019-3-389-127-138</doi><publisherRecordId>25422324</publisherRecordId><documentType>article</documentType><title language="eng">Control of synchronous reluctance motor (synrm) with anisotropic magnetic conductive rotor</title><authors><author><name>Fyodor A. Gelver</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author><author><name>Igor V. Belousov</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author><author><name>Veniamin F. Samoseiko</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author><author><name>Valentin A. Khomyak</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author></authors><affiliationsList><affiliationName affiliationId="1">JSC PO Sevmash</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="2">Admiral Makarov State University of Maritime and Inland Shipping</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="3">St. Petersburg State Marine Technical University</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="4">JSC Alexeev&#8217;s Hydrofoil Design Bureau</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="5">JSC CDB MT Rubin</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="6">RAS Institute of Applied Physics</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="7">JSC Giprorybflot.</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="8">Krylov State Research Centre</affiliationName></affiliationsList><abstract language="eng">Object and purpose of research. This paper discusses development of control system for synchronous reluctance motor with anisotropic magnetic conductive rotor. The purpose of the study is to obtain optimal control algorithms for this motor in terms of response time or power efficiency. Materials and methods. Optimal control algorithms for SynRMs with anisotropic magnetic conductive rotors are obtained through step-by-step correction with tuning to the technical optimum. This study suggests vector-based control algorithms to ensure robustness of SynRM with anisotropic magnetic conductive rotor. Main results. Control algorithms suggested in this paper for SynRM with anisotropic magnetic conductive rotor are robust, i.e. resistant to minor changes in motor parameters, so that dynamic behavior of the motor does not undergo any serious changes. This approach to control system was implemented in the tests of breadboard 500 kW SynRM with anisotropic magnetic conductive rotor. These test data confirmed operability and efficiency of this approach to design of the electric drive based on SynRM with anisotropic magnetic conductive rotor. Conclusion. These control algorithms enable optimal SynRM control in terms of response time or power efficiency, thus making the drives faster and more efficient, and are robust and resistant to minor changes in motor parameters.</abstract><fullTextUrl format="pdf">http://transactions-ksrc.ru/eng/archive/control-of-synchronous-reluctance-motor-synrm-with-anisotropic-magnetic-conductive-rotor/</fullTextUrl><keywords language="eng"><keyword>SynRM</keyword><keyword>magnetic conductance</keyword><keyword>robustness</keyword><keyword>response time</keyword><keyword>power efficiency</keyword></keywords></record><record><language>rus</language><publisher>Krylov State Research Centre</publisher><journalTitle>Transactions of the Krylov State Research Centre</journalTitle><issn>2542-2324</issn><eissn>2618-8244</eissn><publicationDate>2019-08-30</publicationDate><volume>389</volume><issue>3</issue><startPage>139</startPage><endPage>143</endPage><doi>10.24937/2542-2324-2019-3-389-139-143</doi><publisherRecordId>25422324</publisherRecordId><documentType>article</documentType><title language="eng">Boundary conditions of variable magnetic field compensation for a thin ferromagnetic shell</title><authors><author><name>Andrey Ya. Lapovok</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author><author><name>Albert V. Polutov</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author></authors><affiliationsList><affiliationName affiliationId="1">JSC PO Sevmash</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="2">Admiral Makarov State University of Maritime and Inland Shipping</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="3">St. Petersburg State Marine Technical University</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="4">JSC Alexeev&#8217;s Hydrofoil Design Bureau</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="5">JSC CDB MT Rubin</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="6">RAS Institute of Applied Physics</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="7">JSC Giprorybflot.</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="8">Krylov State Research Centre</affiliationName></affiliationsList><abstract language="eng">Object and purpose of research. The purpose of this work was to formulate boundary conditions for density calculations of current sheet compensating low frequency magnetic field of ferromagnetic shell. Materials and methods. Numerical and analytical solution methods for boundary value problems of electromagnetic field theory. Main results. This paper discusses external electromagnetic field compensation of a thin ferromagnetic conductive shell by means of the current sheet on its outer or inner side. For a closed shell, compensating current density is calculated through the solution of internal boundary value problem for a vector magnetic potential with Dirichlet or third kind boundary conditions. Conclusion. The results of this work could be used in development of degaussing device for compensation of the eddy current-induced magnetic field during ship roll. Compensating current must be adjusted with respect to three parameters: Earth magnetic field in ship-axes coordinate system, and two time derivatives of the external field (the first and the second).</abstract><fullTextUrl format="pdf">http://transactions-ksrc.ru/eng/archive/Boundary-conditions-of-variable-magnetic-field-compensation-for-a-thin-ferromagnetic-shell/</fullTextUrl><keywords language="eng"><keyword>low frequency magnetic field</keyword><keyword>thin ferromagnetic shells</keyword><keyword>boundary conditions</keyword><keyword>compensation conditions</keyword></keywords></record><record><language>rus</language><publisher>Krylov State Research Centre</publisher><journalTitle>Transactions of the Krylov State Research Centre</journalTitle><issn>2542-2324</issn><eissn>2618-8244</eissn><publicationDate>2019-08-30</publicationDate><volume>389</volume><issue>3</issue><startPage>144</startPage><endPage>149</endPage><doi>10.24937/2542-2324-2019-3-389-144-149</doi><publisherRecordId>25422324</publisherRecordId><documentType>article</documentType><title language="eng">Vibration-based ssessment method for operation mode and technical condition of ship equipment</title><authors><author><name>Vladislav V. Makarov</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author><author><name>Alexey V. Troitsky</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author></authors><affiliationsList><affiliationName affiliationId="1">JSC PO Sevmash</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="2">Admiral Makarov State University of Maritime and Inland Shipping</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="3">St. Petersburg State Marine Technical University</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="4">JSC Alexeev&#8217;s Hydrofoil Design Bureau</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="5">JSC CDB MT Rubin</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="6">RAS Institute of Applied Physics</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="7">JSC Giprorybflot.</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="8">Krylov State Research Centre</affiliationName></affiliationsList><abstract language="eng">Object and purpose of research. This paper studies vibroacoustic parameters of ship equipment in different operational conditions. The purpose is to develop vibrodiagnostic models of marine equipment and find threshold values for diagnostic parameters to be used in vibration-based monitoring. Materials and methods. The study relies on experimental and statistical research methods. Diagnostic models were constructed as per random process theory and based on the available statistics of failures and faults with ship machinery. Main results. Development of vibration-based method for determination of technical condition of ship machinery and determination of spectrum masks for assessment of its current operational conditions. The method was evaluated at the experimental sample of DRK-2500 pod propulsion unit at the test rig of the manufacturer (the town of Severodvinsk). Conclusion. Mathematical models suggested in this work for monitoring of operational modes and technical conditions of marine equipment working in harsh environments have been successfully developed and tested. This method will enhance operational safety and reliability of ice-class ships.</abstract><fullTextUrl format="pdf">http://transactions-ksrc.ru/eng/archive/Vibration-based-ssessment-method-for-operation-mode-and-technical-condition-of-ship-equipment/</fullTextUrl><keywords language="eng"><keyword>vibroacoustic parameters</keyword><keyword>vibrodiagnostic model</keyword><keyword>ship machinery</keyword><keyword>spectrum mask</keyword></keywords></record><record><language>rus</language><publisher>Krylov State Research Centre</publisher><journalTitle>Transactions of the Krylov State Research Centre</journalTitle><issn>2542-2324</issn><eissn>2618-8244</eissn><publicationDate>2019-08-30</publicationDate><volume>389</volume><issue>3</issue><startPage>150</startPage><endPage>156</endPage><doi>10.24937/2542-2324-2019-3-389-150-156</doi><publisherRecordId>25422324</publisherRecordId><documentType>article</documentType><title language="eng">Prediction of noise radiation from non-uniformities of surface in flow</title><authors><author><name>Anatoly S. Suvorov</name><affiliationId>6</affiliationId></author><author><name>Pavel S. Kalyasov</name><affiliationId>6</affiliationId></author><author><name>Pavel I. Korotin</name><affiliationId>6</affiliationId></author><author><name>Yevgeny M. Sokov</name><affiliationId>6</affiliationId></author><author><name>Viktor V. Artelny</name><affiliationId>6</affiliationId></author></authors><affiliationsList><affiliationName affiliationId="1">JSC PO Sevmash</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="2">Admiral Makarov State University of Maritime and Inland Shipping</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="3">St. Petersburg State Marine Technical University</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="4">JSC Alexeev&#8217;s Hydrofoil Design Bureau</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="5">JSC CDB MT Rubin</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="6">RAS Institute of Applied Physics</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="7">JSC Giprorybflot.</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="8">Krylov State Research Centre</affiliationName></affiliationsList><abstract language="eng">Object and purpose of research. Numerical prediction of hydrodynamic noise induced by flow interaction with non-uniformities of a surface. Materials and methods. The problem is solved by means of hybrid numerical simulation methods for turbulence and direct simulation methods for pseudo-acoustic field dissipation of four-pole sources. Main results. Analysis of noise radiation direction and intensity, physical interpretation of the processes taking place in this phenomenon, demonstration of the possibility to directly apply acoustic test data to various flow patterns. Conclusion. The results of this work could be used in acoustic design of silent hydraulic equipment.</abstract><fullTextUrl format="pdf">http://transactions-ksrc.ru/eng/archive/Prediction-of-noise-radiation-from-non-uniformities-of-surface-in-flow/</fullTextUrl><keywords language="eng"><keyword>computational acoustics</keyword><keyword>flow noise</keyword><keyword>FEM-based simulation</keyword><keyword>hybrid turbulence model</keyword></keywords></record><record><language>rus</language><publisher>Krylov State Research Centre</publisher><journalTitle>Transactions of the Krylov State Research Centre</journalTitle><issn>2542-2324</issn><eissn>2618-8244</eissn><publicationDate>2019-08-30</publicationDate><volume>389</volume><issue>3</issue><startPage>157</startPage><endPage>164</endPage><doi>10.24937/2542-2324-2019-3-389-157-164</doi><publisherRecordId>25422324</publisherRecordId><documentType>article</documentType><title language="eng">Progressive tests of ships</title><authors><author><name>Yuri N. Myasnikov</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author></authors><affiliationsList><affiliationName affiliationId="1">JSC PO Sevmash</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="2">Admiral Makarov State University of Maritime and Inland Shipping</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="3">St. Petersburg State Marine Technical University</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="4">JSC Alexeev&#8217;s Hydrofoil Design Bureau</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="5">JSC CDB MT Rubin</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="6">RAS Institute of Applied Physics</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="7">JSC Giprorybflot.</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="8">Krylov State Research Centre</affiliationName></affiliationsList><abstract language="eng">Object and purpose of research. Analysis and investigation of ship delivery-acceptance tests. Materials and methods. Current procedures of delivery-acceptance tests for ships and vessels. Main results. This paper outlines the main drawback of delivery-acceptance test procedure for ships: this procedure does not take into account technical condition of ship equipment and only measures functional parameters of her propulsion system. Accordingly, a ship in poor technical condition may well pass acceptance tests satisfactorily. Lamentable proofs of this fact are frequent faulties and failures of ships newly built or just after repair. This study suggests an improvement of delivery-acceptance tests based on application of new diagnostic equipment and tools that make sure that the ship is in good order indeed and, most importantly, give a reference model for technical condition of equipment. Practical application of this reference model will not only become the basis of progressive ship testing but will also be helpful in transition to operation of ships and vessel based on their actual technical condition. Conclusion. This paper improves theoretical principles of delivery-acceptance tests of ships and vessels based on new information technologies that enable implementation of progressive test program and yield a tangible and meaningful feedback between ship operators, yards and scientists.</abstract><fullTextUrl format="pdf">http://transactions-ksrc.ru/eng/archive/Progressive-tests-of-ships/</fullTextUrl><keywords language="eng"><keyword>delivery-acceptance tests</keyword><keyword>sea trials</keyword><keyword>safety</keyword><keyword>reference model of technical condition</keyword></keywords></record><record><language>rus</language><publisher>Krylov State Research Centre</publisher><journalTitle>Transactions of the Krylov State Research Centre</journalTitle><issn>2542-2324</issn><eissn>2618-8244</eissn><publicationDate>2019-08-30</publicationDate><volume>389</volume><issue>3</issue><startPage>165</startPage><endPage>172</endPage><doi>10.24937/2542-2324-2019-3-389-165-172</doi><publisherRecordId>25422324</publisherRecordId><documentType>article</documentType><title language="eng">Technological and regulatory support for decontamination of ship ballast waters</title><authors><author><name>Vitaly G. Khoroshev</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author><author><name>Leonid N. Popov</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author><author><name>Ramis I. Gatin</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author><author><name>Nikita P. Pogodin</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author></authors><affiliationsList><affiliationName affiliationId="1">JSC PO Sevmash</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="2">Admiral Makarov State University of Maritime and Inland Shipping</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="3">St. Petersburg State Marine Technical University</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="4">JSC Alexeev&#8217;s Hydrofoil Design Bureau</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="5">JSC CDB MT Rubin</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="6">RAS Institute of Applied Physics</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="7">JSC Giprorybflot.</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="8">Krylov State Research Centre</affiliationName></affiliationsList><abstract language="eng">Object and purpose of research. This paper discusses sea pollution by ship ballast waters. The purpose of this study is to estimate the potential of technological and organizational solutions intended to prevent pollution of Russian seas by ballast waters discharged from ships. Materials and methods. This paper discusses main technological and organizational approaches to ballast water treatment, as envisaged by the rules of International Convention for the Control and Management of Ships&#8217; Ballast Water and Sediments compulsory for the Russian Federation in terms of environmental safety of seas. Main results. This paper presents the results of innovative developments that became the basis for the first Russian ballast water management system (BWMS). It also suggests some additions to the Technical Regulations on Safety of Sea Transport Items to make them compliant with the Convention. Conclusion. BWMS prototype discussed in this paper is reagent-free and eco-friendly, and its technical and economic efficiency is at the level of similar foreign equipment. The additions to the Technical Regulations on Safety of Sea Transport Items suggested in this study are directly connected with ensuring the feasibility of new cost-efficient Russian BWMSs.</abstract><fullTextUrl format="pdf">http://transactions-ksrc.ru/eng/archive/Technological-and-regulatory-support-for-decontamination-of-ship-ballast-waters/</fullTextUrl><keywords language="eng"><keyword>water ballast</keyword><keyword>BWMS</keyword><keyword>ballast water decontamination</keyword><keyword>mechanical filtering</keyword><keyword>UV treatment</keyword></keywords></record><record><language>rus</language><publisher>Krylov State Research Centre</publisher><journalTitle>Transactions of the Krylov State Research Centre</journalTitle><issn>2542-2324</issn><eissn>2618-8244</eissn><publicationDate>2019-08-30</publicationDate><volume>389</volume><issue>3</issue><startPage>173</startPage><endPage>179</endPage><doi>10.24937/2542-2324-2019-3-389-173-179</doi><publisherRecordId>25422324</publisherRecordId><documentType>article</documentType><title language="eng">Operability of threaded and studded joints under intense vibration load</title><authors><author><name>Solon G. Zenkov</name><affiliationId>8</affiliationId></author></authors><affiliationsList><affiliationName affiliationId="1">JSC PO Sevmash</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="2">Admiral Makarov State University of Maritime and Inland Shipping</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="3">St. Petersburg State Marine Technical University</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="4">JSC Alexeev&#8217;s Hydrofoil Design Bureau</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="5">JSC CDB MT Rubin</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="6">RAS Institute of Applied Physics</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="7">JSC Giprorybflot.</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="8">Krylov State Research Centre</affiliationName></affiliationsList><abstract language="eng">Object and purpose of research. This paper discusses threaded and studded joints. Its purpose is to develop and try out the procedure for experimental operability verification of joints under vibration load. Materials and methods. Operational loads on the joints were simulated by means of electrodynamic vibrator. Main results. The study made it possible to develop operability check procedure for threaded and studded joints, including the view of models, testing sequence and list of target parameters. Implementation of this procedure enabled operability checks of full-scale joints under vibration load. Conclusion. The results of this study have confirmed the validity of suggested procedure for experimental operability check of threaded and studded joints under vibration load, as well as confirmed the possibility of their application in hull areas with intense vibration.</abstract><fullTextUrl format="pdf">http://transactions-ksrc.ru/eng/archive/Operability-of-threaded-and-studded-joints-under-intense-vibration-load/</fullTextUrl><keywords language="eng"><keyword>threaded and studded joints</keyword><keyword>vibration strength</keyword><keyword>tightening torque</keyword><keyword>operability</keyword></keywords></record><record><language>rus</language><publisher>Krylov State Research Centre</publisher><journalTitle>Transactions of the Krylov State Research Centre</journalTitle><issn>2542-2324</issn><eissn>2618-8244</eissn><publicationDate>2019-08-30</publicationDate><volume>389</volume><issue>3</issue><startPage>180</startPage><endPage>184</endPage><doi>10.24937/2542-2324-2019-3-389-180-184</doi><publisherRecordId>25422324</publisherRecordId><documentType>article</documentType><title language="eng">Angular alignment of modules in main hull assembling of underwater platform by means of local measurement grids</title><authors><author><name>Mikhail A. Budnichenko</name><affiliationId>1</affiliationId></author><author><name>Aleksandr S. Golubkin</name><affiliationId>5</affiliationId></author><author><name>Dmitry V. Kuzmin</name><affiliationId>1</affiliationId></author></authors><affiliationsList><affiliationName affiliationId="1">JSC PO Sevmash</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="2">Admiral Makarov State University of Maritime and Inland Shipping</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="3">St. Petersburg State Marine Technical University</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="4">JSC Alexeev&#8217;s Hydrofoil Design Bureau</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="5">JSC CDB MT Rubin</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="6">RAS Institute of Applied Physics</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="7">JSC Giprorybflot.</affiliationName><affiliationName affiliationId="8">Krylov State Research Centre</affiliationName></affiliationsList><abstract language="eng">Object and purpose of research. This paper discusses one of the tasks in accurate positioning of large modules during construction of underwater platform as per modular assembling technology. The purpose of the study was to develop and theoretically investigate the method of ensuring angular alignment of the modules by means of local measurement grids and high-precision optical &amp; electronic instrumentation. Materials and methods. Theoretical study of the suggested method for ensuring angular alignment of assembling modules relies on the analytical model of system made up by two interconnected unit modules. This analytical model was constructed as per vector-matrix method commonly used in kinematics of spatial mechanical systems. Main results. The study yielded the method for ensuring angular alignment of underwater platform modules at the berth. The analytical model made up by the two interconnected unit modules has confirmed the correctness of this method and identified its advantages that could be useful for construction practice. Conclusion. The method suggested in this paper is correct and insensitive to linear misalignment of unit modules; the result of its application does not depend on correction sequence of angular misalignments in horizontal and vertical planes. This method could become the basis of high-precision assembling technology for main hull of underwater platform made up by large unit modules.</abstract><fullTextUrl format="pdf">http://transactions-ksrc.ru/eng/archive/angular-alignment-of-modules-in-main-hull-assembling-of-underwater-platform-by-means-of-local-measur/</fullTextUrl><keywords language="eng"><keyword>unit modules</keyword><keyword>alignment</keyword><keyword>local measurement grids</keyword></keywords></record></records>